<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-13T21:59:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Joi’s GitHub Page</title><subtitle>An experimental website to play with Jekyll.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reverse Sear Redux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/12/reverse-sear-redux" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reverse Sear Redux" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/12/reverse-sear-redux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/12/reverse-sear-redux">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reverse-sear-graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reverse Sear Chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rev-sear-board.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Reverse Sear Cutting Board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rev-sear-plated.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Reverse Sear Plated&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did a [[2020-08-02-reverse-sear|reverse sear]] again. This time, the steak from Savenor’s was 2 inches, 1/2 inch thicker than the last time. I wanted to leave plenty of time to cook the steaks so I stuck them into the oven set to 170ºF. I used a remote temperature monitor to track the temperature from my office while it cooked and I kept an eye on my estimated finish time that I calculated by estimating the degrees per minute that it was heating up at each measurement and extrapolating it to my “pull temperature” of 122ºF for a medium-rare doneness after searing and resting - 135ºF serving temperature target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 3:43PM, I realized that my steak was going to arrive an hour early at this rate - I was trying to finish at 5:30PM pull for a 5:45PM sear completion with 15 min for resting, slicing an serving - 6PM serve time. I turned off the oven, but kept the steak in the slowly cooling oven. Because of the residual heat in the oven and the hotter parts of the steak heating the center (where my thermometer was placed), the temperature continued to climb, but slower and slower. At 5:06PM, my oven temperature was 118ºF and I was down to 0.1ºF / min heating so I turned the oven back on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 5:46PM, I hit 122ºF, pulled the steak, seared it on a cast iron skillet and let it rest on the cutting board for 10 min. I then sliced the steak and served. It turned out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely want to improve my calculation for time in the oven, although this thing with turning off the oven seems to work. I also noticed, again, that with my thermometer near the center of the steak pressed against the bone measured a temperature about 4ºF warmer than the center of the colder steak. I wonder what the best way is to guess the coldest part of the steak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Steak&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;ºF / min&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Est. Fin. Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2:38:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.0ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oven set to 170ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2:42:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:46:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2:51:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;49ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6:30:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2:56:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;52ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.6ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:52:40 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:01:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;55ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.6ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:52:40 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:08:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.7ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:34:48 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:15:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;64ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.6ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:56:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:21:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.0ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:13:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:30:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;75ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.6ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:54:36 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:38:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.6ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:45:12 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:43:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;84ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.8ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:30:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turned off oven&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:55:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;91ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.6ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:48:09 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:00:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.4ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:12:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:07:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;96ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.4ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:07:40 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:14:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;98ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:38:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:21:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:38:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:25:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:49:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:30:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.2ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6:10:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:42:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.2ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6:30:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:48:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.2ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6:30:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:06:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;107ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.1ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:21:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turned Oven On&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:14:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;108ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.1ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:06:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:18:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;109ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6:10:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:20:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;110ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.5ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:44:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:26:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;113ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.5ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:44:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:30:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;115ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.5ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:44:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:34:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;117ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.5ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:44:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:46:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;122ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.4ºF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:46:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;118ºF with instant thermometer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My temperature chart from excel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipes" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Perfecting Grilled Salmon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/11/perfecting-grilled-salmon" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Perfecting Grilled Salmon" /><published>2020-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/11/perfecting-grilled-salmon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/11/perfecting-grilled-salmon">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/grilled-salmon-cilantro.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Grilled Salmon with Cilantro Pesto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japanese eat salmon, but my theory is that because it comes from Hokkaido in the far north, Tokyo people never had fresh salmon. Japanese eat salmon heavily salted or cured and cooked well done. It wasn’t until recently that Japanese ate raw salmon and many sushi places still put raw salmon on the “eww” along with other American sushi innovations like mayonnaise and avocado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also see people from Nordic regions eating salmon very rare too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife, who is very Japanese, always finds my American influenced salmon recipes to be way to soft and rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the US, especially the Pacific North West, people eat salmon very rare. Nathan Myhrvold, who hails from Seattle, tell us in &lt;a href=&quot;https://modernistcuisine.com/books/modernist-cuisine-at-home/&quot;&gt;Modernist Cuisine&lt;/a&gt; to pull it from the sous vide at 113ºF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[Pan-Seared-Salmon-Fillets-with-Crispy-Skin|Kenji López-Alt says]] that rare should be 110ºF, medium-rare 120ºF and 130ºF for medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that today I’ll try cooking the salmon to 130ºF using [[Pan-Seared-Salmon-Fillets-with-Crispy-Skin|Kenji López-Alt says]]  for grilling and making the salmon and some [[Grilled-Salmon-with-Cilantro-Pecan-Pesto|cilantro pesto]] on the side for the adults.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Better Mac and Cheese through Chemistry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/10/better-mac-and-cheese-through-chemistry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Better Mac and Cheese through Chemistry" /><published>2020-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/10/better-mac-and-cheese-through-chemistry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/10/better-mac-and-cheese-through-chemistry">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mac-and-cheese.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;mac-and-cheese&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that have been challenging is finding good things for may 3 year old to eat that we can make. One thing that she likes is Annie’s Mac &amp;amp; Cheese. Annie’s boast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made with Goodness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made with organic pasta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made with 100% real cheese&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheese from cows not treated with rBST (no significant difference has been shown between milk derived from rBST-treated and non rBST-treated cows).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We work with trusted suppliers to source only non-GMO ingredients&lt;br /&gt;
No artificial flavors, synthetic colors, or synthetic preservatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried making Mac &amp;amp; Cheese before from various recipes but my daughter didn’t eat it. Also, I found that my Mac &amp;amp; Cheese didn’t keep in the fridge very well - the cheese got hard and the oil separated from the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cheese-and-emulsifier.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Cheese and Emulsifier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I read Modernist Cuisine where they used Sodium Citrate as an emulsifier.[[An emulsifier is a substance that allows oil to be suspended in water or water-based liquids as an emulsion. Eggs, for example, have a natural emulsifier that allows them to be fatty but liquid and mixed together with the water-based part of the egg. The emulsifier in eggs is what allows the oil and vinegar in mayonnaise to be mixed together.::rsn]]They described how this would allow the cheese to become silky smooth - the texture of Annie’s. Looking at the label on Annie’s, I found that it contained Sodium Phosphate as an emulsifier. I think Sodium Citrate comes from citruses whereas Sodium Phosphate comes from Phosphate mines, which clearly isn’t as “natural.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I’ve been having various arguments with people about what is “healthy.” Minerals and simple common molecules found in the body already clearly aren’t “poison.” Having said that, too much of most things is bad for you. I think that it’s important read the research and be careful of consuming too much of anything, especially if it’s been shown to have adverse health effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that molecules designed to kill things like pesticides (bugs), preservatives (microbes), and herbicides (plants) are probably more likely to have adverse side effects than common minerals. Therefore, I agree that the “organic and no preservatives” notations seems helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One theory that I heard from Albert-László Barabási who is &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodome.co/&quot;&gt;researching food&lt;/a&gt; and the chemistry of food and the body was that most living things have very similar metabolic pathways. In fact, the chemicals that are present in most living things and the amounts of these chemicals tend to be roughly a similar distribution. That means that if you eat whole foods, you tend to have a “natural” distribution of chemicals. However, with processed foods, you can end up ingesting unnatural concentrations of certain molecules that throws your body out of whack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this makes a ton of sense and a good reason to keep an eye on high concentrations of anything, especially if your body doesn’t have a natural or easy way of getting rid of the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I think the whole “good for you” “bad for you” business is very complicated because we like to have simple and emotional responses to labels, we don’t have time to keep up with studies. Even if we do read studies, science is constantly flip-flopping on what it thinks is good for us or bad for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think that the best that we can do is try to focus on whole foods, when ingesting lots of anything, look for the science to see if we should be particularly concerned, and try not to make or eat anything that tastes horrible. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/whisked-cheese.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Whisked Cheese&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Modernist Cuisine recipe said to dissolve the Sodium Citrate in milk or water (I used milk) and then slowly melt/whisk in cheddar cheese until you ended up with a creamy liquid. Then boil the macaroni and fold in the cheese sauce. It worked well and tasted great! My daughter didn’t like it though. I’ll try one more time experimenting with different cheeses and maybe make it more mild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do think I got the consistency right. One of the things about Modernist Cuisine is that they use a lot of “chemicals.” Sodium Citrate is one. MSG is another. They also try to “perfect” some of our favorite fast foods like Mac &amp;amp; Cheese and the Big Mac. It’s clearly a different path than the traditionalist cookbooks. I’m enjoying it, but I think I may have lost my wife once plastic bags of white powders with scientific names started showing up on our doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="health" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tuna Confit Redux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/06/tuna-confit-redux" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tuna Confit Redux" /><published>2020-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/06/tuna-confit-redux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/06/tuna-confit-redux">&lt;p&gt;I made [[2020-07-03-tuna-confit|tuna confit]] about a month ago and I used the recipe from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saltfatacidheat.com/&quot;&gt;Nosrat’s book&lt;/a&gt;. I modified it a bit but it involved using a Dutch oven at 150ºF for about 9 min after preparing oil infused with various aromatics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://modernistcuisine.com/books/modernist-cuisine-at-home/&quot;&gt;Modernist Cuisine&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to try it again, but with the sous vide instead. The cool thing that I learned from Modernist Cuisine was that I could use glass jars which could be used to refrigerate the tuna after it was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read various recipes that seemed to have different opinions on whether the product of tuna confit specifically and confit in general was pasteurized and could last for months, weeks or just days. I fine Modernist Cuisine to be the most conservative so I’ll go with them - only keep the tuna for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Modernist Cuisine recipe was pretty straight forward - brine the tuna with salt and sugar for 24 hours. Rinse the tuna, put it in jars and sous vide at 124ºF for a hour or so until the internal temperature of the tuna is 122ºF. Modernist Cuisine doesn’t add any flavor to the tuna so I decided to experiment with one jar including oil infused with black peppercorns, garlic and rosemary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tuna came out nice although the surface of the tuna had little “growths” that looked some something in a petri dish - probably the liquid from inside of the tuna seeping out. The aromatics infused oil tasted better than the plain oil. The tuna was a bit salty - it could have been that I used sea salt that had a higher salt density than the kosher salt. I think I’ll try using less salt next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall it was very nice. I served it with my alioli sauce that went very well with it. I served it for dinner, but I think this tuna is probably a better lunch or breakfast dish - maybe in a sandwich, in a salad or on the side of something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I summarized my current recipe that I’ll try next time - [[Jois-Tuna-Confit|Joi’s Tuna Confit]].&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">I made [[2020-07-03-tuna-confit|tuna confit]] about a month ago and I used the recipe from Nosrat’s book. I modified it a bit but it involved using a Dutch oven at 150ºF for about 9 min after preparing oil infused with various aromatics.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Reverse Sear</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/02/reverse-sear" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Reverse Sear" /><published>2020-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/02/reverse-sear</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/02/reverse-sear">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reverse-sear-steak.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Reverse Sear Steak&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://modernistcuisine.com/&quot;&gt;Nathan Myhvold’s &lt;em&gt;Modernist Cuisine at Home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a beautiful and great book - especially the chemistry and the very “tech” style practical elements such as using emulsifiers for sauces and other more “modern” ingredients and cooking techniques. I got to the chapter on steaks just when my 1.5 inch dry-aged t-bone steaks from Savenor’s were dry-brining in my fridge. Nathan had a number of recommendations including sous vide, slow low-heat oven and BBQ grill with ice pan. I definitely want to try to grill with the pan and I would have gone with sous vide, but my sous vide was being used by the chicken confit… so I decided to go low-heat in the oven. Nathan’s recipe was super low 170ºF or so for 50 min for a 1 inch steak. He said a 2 inch steak could take 3 hours! His recipe called for searing the steak first after a short time in the freezer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking around on the Internet and reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seriouseats.com/2017/03/how-to-reverse-sear-best-way-to-cook-steak.html&quot;&gt;Kenji Lopez’s post on reverse sear&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to go low-heat in the oven with a reverse sear rather than a pre-sear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan had the oven at “160ºF or its lowest temperature setting” whereas Kenji sets the temperature at “between 200 and 275ºF” because “many ovens can’t hold temperatures below 200ºF very accurately.” Nathan is clearly more of a hardware snob. My Wolf oven allowed me to set it at 170ºF but the temperature varied widely between 180 and 213ºF at the middle rack on convection bake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put my 1.5 day, dry-brined, dry-aged beef on a rack with bone side facing the back of the oven and set the temperature to 170ºF. I stuck the steak in at 3:15PM to give me plenty of time. I stuck a thermometer into the edge of the steak and pushed it to intersect with the bone on the inside in the middle of the steak - the part that I thought would be the coldest when completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 10 min, the internal temperature of the meat went from 60ºF to 75ºF. 10 min later, it was at 90ºF - in other words, 15ºF / 10 min. At this rate, I would be up to my target 122ªF in less than one hour. I needed to slow down. At 5PM, I cut the oven and my internal temperature was 124ºF. I decided to let it go a bit past my target since the target of 122ºF includes the increase to 133ºF (my favorite medium-rare temp) as I seared the hot steak and the temperature settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 5:24PM, the steak was at 128ºF, the oven was 180ºF so I pulled the steak. I jammed my instant thermometer in several places and noticed that it was colder in the middle of the meat than by the bone. Unbelievable! Probably a combination of the bone facing the back of the oven and it sitting there for so long was the cause. In the middle of the meat, I recorded a 119ºF reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set the oven to 220ºF and put the steak back in. At 5:35PM I pulled the steak again, this time with recording 122ºF at the coldest spot with my instant thermometer. Interestingly, the smell (probably because there is no sear) of the steak and the oven weren’t really that great - sort of funky actually. I seared it on a cast iron skillet with oil for around 1 min per side, tossing in some butter at the very end. The steak was so dry it barely sizzled, but it seared perfectly - crisp, brown, wonderful smell. I sliced the steak and served it with soy sauce and wasabi. It was a tad over-done. However, was very good and tasted almost like &lt;em&gt;wagyu&lt;/em&gt;. It may have been one of the best steaks I’ve made. I think the very slow cook caused an incredibly complex chemical reaction with the perfect sear at the end. Yum!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back of the oven, I had heard, is hotter than the middle. With the convection oven, it might even be amplified if just in front of the vent. Will measure next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reverse sear works especially well because the surface of the meat was super-dry compared to pre-sear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverse sear is more difficult to time than pre-sear because there is more of a range of temperature change after pulling the steak because of the sear. The appropriate temperature to pull the steak is made even more difficult if the temperature of the oven has been changed because the speed of transmission of internal temperature from the outside to the inside is less “known.” However, putting the sear at the end times the sear perfectly before serving vs the pre-sear which probably tastes and smells better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sharpening, Honing, Stropping</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/29/sharpening-honing-stropping" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sharpening, Honing, Stropping" /><published>2020-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/29/sharpening-honing-stropping</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/29/sharpening-honing-stropping">&lt;p&gt;Sharpening is making a dull knife sharp. Honing is maintaining a sharp knife. Most razor people call what they do honing - experts are called honemasters or honemeisters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stropping is when you use an even finer material such as leather to remove the burr and any extra material, straighten the edge and make the blade even sharper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people bundle it into “sharpening” or put it into “restoring” but blades often need to have their “bevel” set. The bevel is the face of the actual cutting part of the blade. There can either be one or two bevels depending on whether the blade is sharpened on both side. Even “single bevel” blades such as the single bevel Japanese sushi knife and razor have a tiny bevel on the back side, but are just sharpening at an asymmetrical ratio such as 10:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is to use a fairly rough stone such as a 400 grit stone to fix any major damage. Then use something around 1000 grit to set the bevel. Then you go to increasingly finer stones such as 3000 grit, 8000 grit, etc. to progressively sharpen and polish that edge rubbing out the scratches from the previous stone with smaller scratches from the new stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the last, “finishing stone,” often a natural stone such as a Japanese natural whetstone or a Belgian Coticule, you polish and finish the blade. On the natural stones, because the “slurry” (the soft material that comes off of the stone as you hone) breaks down into finer material and because the stone itself is made up of non-uniform particle sizes, using less pressure on the blade can sharpen at a progressively softer rate - apparently more than synthetic stones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have the mirror finish from the finishing stone, you really clean it up and make the edge razor sharp and smooth by giving a few laps on the strop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is my understanding of the general flow as of this writing, but I keep learning more and more… Yesterday, for example, I learned that many German sharpeners use convex stone surfaces to give the honemeister more control of where the stone touches the blade and allow more fine control whereas the Japanese seem to always want a perfectly flat stone for razors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/myfirstjnat.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My First JNat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I got my first Japanese natural stone and some &lt;em&gt;Mikawa&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;nagura&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;awasedo&lt;/em&gt; that I got was a &lt;em&gt;Shobundani&lt;/em&gt; and I got a &lt;em&gt;Botan&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tanjyou&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mejiro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Koma nagura&lt;/em&gt; along with a &lt;em&gt;tomo nagura&lt;/em&gt;. I got them as a set on Etsy from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomonagura.com/&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got my &lt;em&gt;Iwasaki&lt;/em&gt; Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; razor. I tried to shave out of the box. In addition to my crappy lathering, I didn’t really have the hang of shaving and I ended up with lots of little bloody spots. I stopped part way through and decided to try to hone the blade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at it under my loupe and got a good sense of the marks on the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looked like the bevel was already set but that it needed an edge honing so I put it on my &lt;em&gt;Yoshihiro&lt;/em&gt; 3000 and then moved to the &lt;em&gt;Shobundani awasedo&lt;/em&gt; using progressively the &lt;em&gt;Botan&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tanjyou&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mejiro&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Koma&lt;/em&gt; and then eventually to &lt;em&gt;tomo&lt;/em&gt;. I shaved (dry) after each stone and looked at the edge under the loupe to get a sense of how each stone sharpened the blade. It was quite amazing that I could see and feel (or thought I could feel) a slightly better edge after each stone. By the end, I could DEFINITELY feel a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a (still fairly crappy) new lather and tried it out “for real”. I was a bit too tired to do a whole shave, but in the few sections that I gave a real try at, the shave went very well. So excited. I can go to bed now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sharpening" /><summary type="html">Sharpening is making a dull knife sharp. Honing is maintaining a sharp knife. Most razor people call what they do honing - experts are called honemasters or honemeisters.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Japanese Kamisori Razors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/kamisori-razors" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japanese Kamisori Razors" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/kamisori-razors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/kamisori-razors">&lt;p&gt;As I tumble down the rat hole of sharpening and honing, I stumbled into the rat hole that is Japanese kamisori razors. They are similar to the straight single edged razors in the West, but they only have one side beveled - similar to Japanese swords. Apparently the were introduced into Japan when monks brought razors to shave their heads. Shaving men’s faces came with the Western influence of the Meiji Restoration. The Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; or razor is made like a Japanese knife or sword. When low cost sharp razors came onto the market, &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; mostly disappeared. Sharpening them takes a long time and a lot of expertise and they are expensive to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is a kind of cult following in the West and people obsessively hone and shave with &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt;. Mizuka Googled in Japanese and there are still a few barbershops in Japan that use them, but they are mostly out of circulation. The Japanese website also noted that they are a “thing” among Western &lt;em&gt;otaku&lt;/em&gt;. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I dig into sharpening and honing I end up in forums where people are talking about whetstones and the conversation inevitably leads you to the razor honing community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never really needed lots of razors because I don’t have a lot of facial hair, but I’m going to give a &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; a try. Most &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; on Esty or eBay are antiques (as are many Japanese whetstones) because they don’t make or use them so much anymore. The good thing is that if you sharpen up an old &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt;, it should be as good as new. Luckily, stones also don’t spoil with age, but they do become expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharpologist.com/a-kamisori-primer/&quot;&gt;[Here’s a post about Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sharpening" /><category term="kamisori" /><summary type="html">As I tumble down the rat hole of sharpening and honing, I stumbled into the rat hole that is Japanese kamisori razors. They are similar to the straight single edged razors in the West, but they only have one side beveled - similar to Japanese swords. Apparently the were introduced into Japan when monks brought razors to shave their heads. Shaving men’s faces came with the Western influence of the Meiji Restoration. The Japanese kamisori or razor is made like a Japanese knife or sword. When low cost sharp razors came onto the market, kamisori mostly disappeared. Sharpening them takes a long time and a lot of expertise and they are expensive to make.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BBQ Grilled Spicy Thai-Style Skirt Steak</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/25/spicy-thai-steak-salad" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BBQ Grilled Spicy Thai-Style Skirt Steak" /><published>2020-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/25/spicy-thai-steak-salad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/25/spicy-thai-steak-salad">&lt;p&gt;I had some skirt steak left over in the freezer and wasn’t so exited about cooking it - my image was dried, tough fajitas. Then, I noticed that Nosrat said it was her favorite “weekday steak” and that Kenji thought it was even more tasty than a rib eye. The problem was is that it’s thin and easily turns tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In The Food Lab, Kenji says that if you cook it correctly, it can be really good. He says you have to sear it very quickly over a very high heat. Kenji says that the &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/The-Food-Lab---Spicy-Thai-Style-Flank-Steak-Salad.html&quot;&gt;[Spicy Thai-Style Flank Steak Salad]&lt;/a&gt; was one of his favorite so I was excited to try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used hardwood charcoal which burns faster and hotter. After heating the coals in the chimney, I put them in the grill to one side and pours a healthy extra layer of fresh coals on top to make it super hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grilled them starting with the thickest piece first on the hot side on both sides and them moved them to the cooler side of the grill as I added new pieces. I pulled them at 120ºF or so in the coolest part and let them finish on the cool side. They quickly got hotter - 135ºF or so, but came out OK. The recipe was excellent and maybe the best thing I’ve ever made on my grill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also grilled burgers and veggies - summer squash and zucchini. I used the recipe we stumbled on when we put dressing on them before - salt, olive oil and some vinegar tossing before grilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything was better with the hotter grill other than burning the hairs on my hand and melting part of my thermometer. I’ll have to use the protective gloves and be more careful about what I put near the grill.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">I had some skirt steak left over in the freezer and wasn’t so exited about cooking it - my image was dried, tough fajitas. Then, I noticed that Nosrat said it was her favorite “weekday steak” and that Kenji thought it was even more tasty than a rib eye. The problem was is that it’s thin and easily turns tough.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sharpening and Honing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/sharpening-honing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sharpening and Honing" /><published>2020-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/sharpening-honing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/sharpening-honing">&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten into sharpening my knives on and off over the decades since I lived in Chicago and the sushi chef at the local sushi shop, first taught me how to handle a Japanese knife and sharpen it. I’ve always enjoyed sharpening knives and each time I “get into it” I seem to go a bit deeper. However, I found it hard to learn to sharpen without a good teacher and I didn’t have the time, energy or the opportunity to apprentice anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I started ramping up my cooking during COVID, I realized that my knives needed work. I pulled out my old stones and tried to sharpen my knives. One knife didn’t sharpen well so I started googling. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a TON of information - YouTube videos, dedicated forums and blogs… all about sharpening and honing. I read a bunch of stuff, bought a few more stones and started again. I realized that my bevel was messed up so I looked up how to set a bevel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I noticed reading about people obsessing about sharpening razors… Then I discovered Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; razors and Japanese natural stones… then nagura stones to create slurry. This feels like a real deep end that I’m falling into where I don’t yet know what I don’t know - like when I started scuba diving. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think I’ll start writing more about my [[My Whetstones]] and other sharpening and honing things on this site now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few links I’ve read about stones and honing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomonagura.com/jnats/japanese-whetstone-info/buying-jnats---first-last.html&quot;&gt;http://www.tomonagura.com/jnats/japanese-whetstone-info/buying-jnats---first-last.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.japanesenaturalstones.com/razors-on-jnat/&quot;&gt;https://www.japanesenaturalstones.com/razors-on-jnat/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coticule.be/japanese-hones-a-traditional-approach.html&quot;&gt;http://www.coticule.be/japanese-hones-a-traditional-approach.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sharpening" /><summary type="html">I’ve gotten into sharpening my knives on and off over the decades since I lived in Chicago and the sushi chef at the local sushi shop, first taught me how to handle a Japanese knife and sharpen it. I’ve always enjoyed sharpening knives and each time I “get into it” I seem to go a bit deeper. However, I found it hard to learn to sharpen without a good teacher and I didn’t have the time, energy or the opportunity to apprentice anywhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whole Chickens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/23/whole-chicken" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whole Chickens" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/23/whole-chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/23/whole-chicken">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saltfatacidheat.com/&quot;&gt;Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat&lt;/a&gt;, Nosrat aruges for buying whole chickens rather than buying parts. You can save the spine and other parts for stock and cut the pieces yourself. It’s cheaper and it’s my own anecdotal feel, but it seems like the whole chickens that we get from &lt;a href=&quot;https://farmerstoyou.com/&quot;&gt;Farmers To You&lt;/a&gt; are fresher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve cooked a whole chicken every week for the last month or so. This week, Farmers To You didn’t have whole chicken so I ordered a &lt;a href=&quot;http://giannonepoultry.com/en/&quot;&gt;Giannone chicken&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savenorsmarket.com/&quot;&gt;Savenor’s&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed like it was frozen at one point (some parts were still frozen). Are all / most chickens frozen? The beef kebabs yesterday from Farmers To You were partially frozen too. I wonder what the logic is to sell frozen meats thawed. Is it marketing? Is it so people can prepare it without thawing? Is it that they are frozen in some way that is less damaging than a home fridge? Is it lower temperature. Hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Giannone chicken from Savenor’s is also smaller - 3 lb vs the 5.5 lb chickens that I’d been getting from Farmers To You. I  [[Jois-Oven-Roasted-Spatchcocked-Chicken|spatchcocked]] it yesterday, salt and peppered it and stuck it in the fridge. I plan to try putting a weight (second cast iron pan) on top of the chicken when I sear it this time to see how it goes. (I heard about it and then found [[Spatchcocked Chicken “Under a Brick”|this “Spatchcocked Chicken Under A Brick” recipe]].) I’ll try it at 450ºF per this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took the spine and wing tips from the Giannone chicken, added it to the celery, parsley and left over chicken parts in the freezer along with three points of chicken bones from Savenor’s and the rest of the [[Samin-Nosrat-Chicken-Stock|recipe for Nosrat’s chicken stock recipe]] and simmered it for 6 hours yesterday. It’s currently chilling in the wine cellar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to use the stock to make [[Risotto-Primavera]] as the side dish tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risotto turned out nice. I used porcini instead of shiitake which turned the whole thing a bit brown, but otherwise it was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chicken was good, but my Chugod thermometers got the temperature wrong (I don’t think it was user error) but I used the Javelin Pro and used it to get it to the right temperature. I use the Chugod because it can stay connected when the food is in the oven and it has a Bluetooth mode that allows me to monitor it on my phone. However, the range doesn’t allow me to use it outside, in my office or on the 3 fl nursery and it complains loudly both at the device and on my phone when it gets disconnected… which is annoying. It is hard to figure out exactly where to measure on a spatchcocked chicken since there is no “middle” of the chicken, but I think near the bone seemed best. I need to get better at placing the thermometer maybe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="theory" /><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">In Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat, Nosrat aruges for buying whole chickens rather than buying parts. You can save the spine and other parts for stock and cut the pieces yourself. It’s cheaper and it’s my own anecdotal feel, but it seems like the whole chickens that we get from Farmers To You are fresher.</summary></entry></feed>