<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-27T20:00:56-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Joi’s GitHub Page</title><subtitle>An experimental website to play with Jekyll.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Japanese Kamisori Razors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/kamisori-razors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japanese Kamisori Razors" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/kamisori-razors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/kamisori-razors.html">&lt;p&gt;As I tumble down the rat hole of sharpening and honing, I stumbled into the rat hole that is Japanese kamisori razors. They are similar to the straight single edged razors in the West, but they only have one side beveled - similar to Japanese swords. Apparently the were introduced into Japan when monks brought razors to shave their heads. Shaving men’s faces came with the Western influence of the Meiji Restoration. The Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; or razor is made like a Japanese knife or sword. When low cost sharp razors came onto the market, &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; mostly disappeared. Sharpening them takes a long time and a lot of expertise and they are expensive to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a kind of cult following in the West and people obsessively hone and shave with &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt;. Mizuka Googled in Japanese and there are still a few barbershops in Japan that use them, but they are mostly out of circulation. The Japanese website also noted that they are a “thing” among Western &lt;em&gt;otaku&lt;/em&gt;. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I dig into sharpening and honing I end up in forums where people are talking about whetstones and the conversation inevitably leads you to the razor honing community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never really needed lots of razors because I don’t have a lot of facial hair, but I’m going to give a &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; a try. Most &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; on Esty or eBay are antiques (as are many Japanese whetstones) because they don’t make or use them so much anymore. The good thing is that if you sharpen up an old &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt;, it should be as good as new. Luckily, stones also don’t spoil with age, but they do become expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a post about Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt;.  https://sharpologist.com/a-kamisori-primer/&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sharpening," /><category term="kamisori" /><summary type="html">As I tumble down the rat hole of sharpening and honing, I stumbled into the rat hole that is Japanese kamisori razors. They are similar to the straight single edged razors in the West, but they only have one side beveled - similar to Japanese swords. Apparently the were introduced into Japan when monks brought razors to shave their heads. Shaving men’s faces came with the Western influence of the Meiji Restoration. The Japanese kamisori or razor is made like a Japanese knife or sword. When low cost sharp razors came onto the market, kamisori mostly disappeared. Sharpening them takes a long time and a lot of expertise and they are expensive to make.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BBQ Grilled Spicy Thai-Style Skirt Steak</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/25/spicy-thai-steak-salad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BBQ Grilled Spicy Thai-Style Skirt Steak" /><published>2020-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/25/spicy-thai-steak-salad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/25/spicy-thai-steak-salad.html">&lt;p&gt;I had some skirt steak left over in the freezer and wasn’t so exited about cooking it - my image was dried, tough fajitas. Then, I noticed that Nosrat said it was her favorite “weekday steak” and that Kenji thought it was even more tasty than a rib eye. The problem was is that it’s thin and easily turns tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In The Food Lab, Kenji says that if you cook it correctly, it can be really good. He says you have to sear it very quickly over a very high heat. Kenji says that the &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/The-Food-Lab---Spicy-Thai-Style-Flank-Steak-Salad.html&quot;&gt;[Spicy Thai-Style Flank Steak Salad]&lt;/a&gt; was one of his favorite so I was excited to try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used hardwood charcoal which burns faster and hotter. After heating the coals in the chimney, I put them in the grill to one side and pours a healthy extra layer of fresh coals on top to make it super hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grilled them starting with the thickest piece first on the hot side on both sides and them moved them to the cooler side of the grill as I added new pieces. I pulled them at 120ºF or so in the coolest part and let them finish on the cool side. They quickly got hotter - 135ºF or so, but came out OK. The recipe was excellent and maybe the best thing I’ve ever made on my grill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also grilled burgers and veggies - summer squash and zucchini. I used the recipe we stumbled on when we put dressing on them before - salt, olive oil and some vinegar tossing before grilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was better with the hotter grill other than burning the hairs on my hand and melting part of my thermometer. I’ll have to use the protective gloves and be more careful about what I put near the grill.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">I had some skirt steak left over in the freezer and wasn’t so exited about cooking it - my image was dried, tough fajitas. Then, I noticed that Nosrat said it was her favorite “weekday steak” and that Kenji thought it was even more tasty than a rib eye. The problem was is that it’s thin and easily turns tough.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sharpening and Honing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/sharpening-honing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sharpening and Honing" /><published>2020-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/sharpening-honing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/sharpening-honing.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten into sharpening my knives on and off over the decades since I lived in Chicago and the sushi chef at the local sushi shop, first taught me how to handle a Japanese knife and sharpen it. I’ve always enjoyed sharpening knives and each time I “get into it” I seem to go a bit deeper. However, I found it hard to learn to sharpen without a good teacher and I didn’t have the time, energy or the opportunity to apprentice anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started ramping up my cooking during COVID, I realized that my knives needed work. I pulled out my old stones and tried to sharpen my knives. One knife didn’t sharpen well so I started googling. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a TON of information - YouTube videos, dedicated forums and blogs… all about sharpening and honing. I read a bunch of stuff, bought a few more stones and started again. I realized that my bevel was messed up so I looked up how to set a bevel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I noticed reading about people obsessing about sharpening razors… Then I discovered Japanese &lt;em&gt;kamisori&lt;/em&gt; razors and Japanese natural stones… then nagura stones to create slurry. This feels like a real deep end that I’m falling into where I don’t yet know what I don’t know - like when I started scuba diving. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think I’ll start writing more about my [[whetstones]] and other sharpening and honing things on this site now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few links I’ve read about stones and honing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://www.tomonagura.com/jnats/japanese-whetstone-info/buying-jnats—first-last.html&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.japanesenaturalstones.com/razors-on-jnat/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://www.coticule.be/japanese-hones-a-traditional-approach.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sharpening" /><summary type="html">I’ve gotten into sharpening my knives on and off over the decades since I lived in Chicago and the sushi chef at the local sushi shop, first taught me how to handle a Japanese knife and sharpen it. I’ve always enjoyed sharpening knives and each time I “get into it” I seem to go a bit deeper. However, I found it hard to learn to sharpen without a good teacher and I didn’t have the time, energy or the opportunity to apprentice anywhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whole Chickens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/23/whole-chicken.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whole Chickens" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/23/whole-chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/23/whole-chicken.html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saltfatacidheat.com/&quot;&gt;[Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat]&lt;/a&gt;, Nosrat aruges for buying whole chickens rather than buying parts. You can save the spine and other parts for stock and cut the pieces yourself. It’s cheaper and it’s my own anecdotal feel, but it seems like the whole chickens that we get from &lt;a href=&quot;https://farmerstoyou.com/&quot;&gt;[Farmers To You]&lt;/a&gt; are fresher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve cooked a whole chicken every week for the last month or so. This week, Farmers To You didn’t have whole chicken so I ordered a &lt;a href=&quot;http://giannonepoultry.com/en/&quot;&gt;[Giannone chicken]&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savenorsmarket.com/&quot;&gt;[Savenor’s]&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed like it was frozen at one point (some parts were still frozen). Are all / most chickens frozen? The beef kebabs yesterday from Farmers To You were partially frozen too. I wonder what the logic is to sell frozen meats thawed. Is it marketing? Is it so people can prepare it without thawing? Is it that they are frozen in some way that is less damaging than a home fridge? Is it lower temperature. Hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Giannone chicken from Savenor’s is also smaller - 3 lb vs the 5.5 lb chickens that I’d been getting from Farmers To You. I &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Jois-Oven-Roasted-Spatchcocked-Chicken.html&quot;&gt;[spatchcocked]&lt;/a&gt; it yesterday, salt and peppered it and stuck it in the fridge. I plan to try putting a weight (second cast iron pan) on top of the chicken when I sear it this time to see how it goes. (I heard about it and then found &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Spatchcocked-Chicken-Under-a-Brick.html&quot;&gt;[this “Spatchcocked Chicken Under A Brick” recipe]&lt;/a&gt;.) I’ll try it at 450ºF per this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the spine and wing tips from the Giannone chicken, added it to the celery, parsley and left over chicken parts in the freezer along with three points of chicken bones from Savenor’s and the rest of the &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Samin-Nosrat-Chicken-Stock.html&quot;&gt;[recipe for Nosrat’s chicken stock recipe]&lt;/a&gt; and simmered it for 6 hours yesterday. It’s currently chilling in the wine cellar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to use the stock to make &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Risotto-Primavera.html&quot;&gt;[Risotto Primavera]&lt;/a&gt; as the side dish tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risotto turned out nice. I used porcini instead of shiitake which turned the whole thing a bit brown, but otherwise it was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chicken was good, but my Chugod thermometers got the temperature wrong (I don’t think it was user error) but I used the Javelin Pro and used it to get it to the right temperature. I use the Chugod because it can stay connected when the food is in the oven and it has a Bluetooth mode that allows me to monitor it on my phone. However, the range doesn’t allow me to use it outside, in my office or on the 3 fl nursery and it complains loudly both at the device and on my phone when it gets disconnected… which is annoying. It is hard to figure out exactly where to measure on a spatchcocked chicken since there is no “middle” of the chicken, but I think near the bone seemed best. I need to get better at placing the thermometer maybe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="theory," /><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">In [Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat], Nosrat aruges for buying whole chickens rather than buying parts. You can save the spine and other parts for stock and cut the pieces yourself. It’s cheaper and it’s my own anecdotal feel, but it seems like the whole chickens that we get from [Farmers To You] are fresher.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Mexican Side Dish</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/16/mexican-side-dish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Mexican Side Dish" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/16/mexican-side-dish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/16/mexican-side-dish.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mexican-coleslaw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Mexican Coleslaw&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A* is making Chili Con Carne with Nachos and Guacamole. I’m supposed to make the side dish. My guess is that lime, coriander and red onions are a good place to start. Maybe I’ll make a salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And… we don’t have lettuce. But we have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sienafarms.com/csa/peak-season-farm-share-faq/&quot;&gt;Siena Farms&lt;/a&gt; share coming today so there might be something, but they sometimes show up right at dinner time. Maybe I’ll do a Mexican cole slaw as a backup recipe since I recall seeing a bit of cabbage in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Mexican Coleslaw came out great. I followed a recipe [[Mexican Coleslaw With Cilantro Lime Dressing]] and the only thing missing was bell peppers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* “A” is the initial of our Au Pair housemate who is cooking this evening.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Diving into Salsa Verde - Spatchcocked Chicken redux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/15/salsa-verde.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diving into Salsa Verde - Spatchcocked Chicken redux" /><published>2020-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/15/salsa-verde</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/15/salsa-verde.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/salsa-verde.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Salsa Verde&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The daughter of our housemates really liked the Spatchcocked Chicken last week so we decided that we should make it again this week. It would add more fodder for my stock bag in the freezer and would help me work on perfecting the recipe. Since we need to make it today, we’ll get a chance to taste it without an overnight brining to see if we can taste the difference. (We should do this side-by-side sometime.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skin wasn’t ask crispy. I used a thermometer to monitor the temperature. It was hard to figure out where to place the thermometer. When I used the hand-held thermometer to check temperatures in other places after my alarm went off, I founder some cooler spots so had to cook it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/spatchcocked-thermometer.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Spatchcocked Thermometer&quot; height=&quot;%50&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/spatchcocked-temp.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spatchcocked Temperature&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was about a total of 45 min subtracting time for the removal and replacement of the chicken. There was some red in the joints, bones and juice from the joints so it seems like I should have cooked it a bit longer, but generally it seemed done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I noticed was that we have fresh herbs expiring on different cycles and I noticed that the &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Basic-Salsa-Verde.html&quot;&gt;Salsa Verde&lt;/a&gt; and various herb sauces in Salt Fat Acid Heat were pretty flexible and great for side sauces for things like the Spatchcocked Chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have extra parsley and sage today so I’ll make the Salsa Verde and possibly fry the sage and make the &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Fried-Sage-Salsa-Verde.html&quot;&gt;Fried Sage Salsa Verde&lt;/a&gt; if I have time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="spatchcocked-chicken" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crown Roast of Lamb</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/14/crown-roast-of-lamb.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crown Roast of Lamb" /><published>2020-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/14/crown-roast-of-lamb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/14/crown-roast-of-lamb.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/carved-roast-crown.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Carved Crown Roast&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mizuka was talking to our house guest* who doesn’t like lamb. Mizuka explained that she didn’t like lamb either but that she started liking it after she first had a Crown Roast of Lamb over the holidays that we bought from Savenor’s so we decided to try it to see if it would change our guest’s taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at three recipes and decided to dry brine over night but to add the spice rub at lunch. I think I could have spiced it last night as well, but it was late. I thought that the salt was probably the most important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m mashing up three receipts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Crown-Roast-of-Lamb-with-Rosemary-and-Oregano---Epicurious.html&quot;&gt;Epicurious - Crown Roast of Lamb with Rosemary and Oregano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Crown-Roast-of-Lamb---Food-Network.html&quot;&gt;Food Network - Crown Roast of Lamb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Crown-Roast-of-Lamb---Thermoworks.html&quot;&gt;Thermoworks - Crown Roast of Lamb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used 2 tbsp of fresh rosemary, 6 garlic cloves, 1 tsp of dried oregano, 2 tbsp of chopped parsley, 1/2 tsp of lemon zest, 1 1/2 tsp salt, 1 tsp of ground pepper, 1 tsp of fresh thyme. I dry brined the lamb from the morning, then oiled the lamb with light olive oil and spread the rub over the lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/crown-roast-oven.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crown Roast in Oven&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set the oven to 425ºF and roasted it on a skillet (heated together with the oven) and covered the bones with foil. I put a thermometer into the meat with an alarm at 125ºF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/crown-roast-cut.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Crown Roast in Oven&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;I forgot to take a photo of the crown before I cut the twine. This is roughly the shape that it was, but maybe not quite as flat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took nearly one hour to cook. I now realize that this is probably because the “hole” in the middle was gone because it was shaped more like pursed lips than a crown because of the way it came from Savenor’s. I think that next time, I need to shape it into a crown and maybe tie the two ends together to hold it in that shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the lamb looked more “medium” than “medium-rare”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Food Network recipe said to use the drippings to make a sauce with 1 tbsp vinegar and 1 tsp of Dijon mustard. The pan drippings were almost all oil which was too hot. Next time, I should remove the oil and cool down the pan before adding the vinegar and the mustard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I complied this into &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Jois-Crown-Roast-of-Lamb.html&quot;&gt;a recipe.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* We have had a family of friends with two kids living in our au pair since early in the lockdown. It’s been fun cooking with and for them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Soft-Shell Crab à la Martha Stewart</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/13/soft-shell-crab.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Soft-Shell Crab à la Martha Stewart" /><published>2020-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/13/soft-shell-crab</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/13/soft-shell-crab.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/soft-shell-crab.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Soft-Shell Crab&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered 4 soft-shell crabs from Savenor’s and I cooked them based on a &lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/Pan-Fried-Soft-Shell-Crabs.html&quot;&gt;Martha Stewart recipe&lt;/a&gt;. Mizuka doesn’t like to waste oil so I didn’t put as much as in the recipe. They came out OK, but were a bit soggier than I’d want - I think the temperature went down. I think that I could either fry fewer crabs at a time (I put 4 in the pan), use more oil or make it hotter before adding the crabs. I think I’ll try all of these things the next time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BBQ Shrimp, Burgers, Sausage and Steak</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/bbq-shrimp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BBQ Shrimp, Burgers, Sausage and Steak" /><published>2020-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/bbq-shrimp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/bbq-shrimp.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020-07-12-bbq-spread.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;BBQ Spread&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;BBQ Spread. The coffee maker just happened to be in the shot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s another BBQ day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the current thinking on the recipes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;grilled-shrimp&quot;&gt;Grilled Shrimp&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lemon
Soak skewers so they don’t burn. Towel-dry garlic, a and marinate with olive oil, salt, epper, paprika, garlic and lemon. Grill. Pretty straight forward. I might add some parsely at the end for a herb smell and look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;burgers&quot;&gt;Burgers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients-1&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lb ground beef&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp minced onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp Worcestershire sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 3/4 tsp ground pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sausage&quot;&gt;Sausage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sous Vide at 150ºF and grilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;grilled-sirloin-steak&quot;&gt;Grilled Sirloin Steak&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salt and pepper seasoned and stuck in the fridge this morning. Will just grill and serve with hot sauce and aioli sauce on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/roast-first.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;BBQ Spread&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tried low indirect heat first, brought steak to 115ºF then seared over direct heat to 125ºF. Got a nice “look” on the steak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed a recipe for the shrimp marinade and it turned out salty. I guess I need to season marinades to taste, but that’s tricky…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">BBQ Spread. The coffee maker just happened to be in the shot.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Steamed Lobster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/11/steamed-lobster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Steamed Lobster" /><published>2020-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/11/steamed-lobster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/11/steamed-lobster.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lobster-pot.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Lobsters in pot&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have four 1½ lb lobsters today and after googling around I find a range of recipes for steaming them starting 9-11 min at &lt;a href=&quot;https://lobsteranywhere.com/cooking-lobster/&quot;&gt;Lobster Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; and up to 14 min according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lobsteranywhere.com/cooking-lobster/&quot;&gt;Lobster from Maine&lt;/a&gt;. You’d think that steaming would be approximately the same amount of time since the temperature is probably roughly the same? I guess maybe not. Or maybe it is about the preferred “doneness.” But both recipes are American. I guess I’ll try 11 min and see how it goes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one larger female with roe inside and it wasn’t done at 11 min. I’m not sure if it was bigger or whether the eggs made it take longer but I had to steam it more. The other lobsters were on the rare side but OK. Maybe safer to do 12-13 min for 1½ lb lobsters. I think that it took a few min for the pot to heat up again after adding them - which might have an effect on the time… but we were using a very large lobster steaming pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roe is black when it’s not cooked, but turns red and much tastier when cooked. I can’t believe that many Americans call it “wax” and don’t eat it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>